Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Heat. Heat up
[Music]
here.
Heat.
[Music]
Heat
up here.
[Music]
Amen. Amen.
Um that opening uh graphic
team, well done. Well done. Well done.
You all put a one in the
chat if you are ready to get into the
word of God uh this morning. We're going
to be looking especially
um at Jesus in a very beautiful way
today.
uh we're going to pull we're going to
pull some some very powerful lessons
from the scripture. And so again, if
you're ready to get into the chat into
the into the uh sermon today, um put a
one in the chat
um if you want others to be a part of
this
blessing, share this
link. Share this
link. Uh, in fact, throughout this
sermon, I think instead of saying put a
one in the chat, I'm going to say if you
understand, if you're if you are liking
what you're hearing, I'm gonna ask you
to hit that share
button. That's what I'm going to ask.
I'm going to ask you to hit that like
button. I'm going to ask you to hit that
subscribe
button. Um, so we can get this message
out, so we can share this living manner.
So, let's pray you all. We're going to
jump into the scriptures. Uh, let's seek
the Lord's face now. Heavenly
Father, Lord, we ask that you would
please speak to us again, Lord. Open
your word, open our hearts, grant us
wisdom and understanding. We pray this
in Jesus name. Amen. And
amen.
Trusting the son of David. Trusting the
son of David. Let's go to the screen.
Let's go to the screen
and I want you to note with
me the book of
Luke chapter
1 beginning with verse 31. Luke 1:31.
The Bible says, "And behold, thou shalt
conceive, thou shalt conceive in thy
womb and bring forth a son, and shall
call his
name
Jesus. He shall be great, and shall be
called the Son of the Highest.
And the Lord shall give unto him the
throne of his father David. And he shall
reign over the house of Jacob
forever. And of his kingdom there shall
be no end. The Bible tells us that this
savior who was to come into the world,
his name would be called
Jesus. His name would be called Jesus.
He would reign and of his kingdom there
would be no end. There would be no end.
The Bible tells us in Luke 22 and verse
21, "And when eight days were
accomplished
uh for the circumcision of the child,
his name was called
Jesus, which was so named of the angel
before he was conceived in the womb. It
was on the eighth day that Jesus
received his name."
[Music]
Um, I want you to keep this in mind as
we
begin to walk through these
verses. The Bible says in Matthew 1:21,
"And she shall bring forth a son, and
thou shalt call his name Jesus, for he
shall save his people from their sins."
This is why he was to receive the name
Jesus because he would save his
people from their sins. Again in John 1
29 the Bible says in John the next day
John seeth Jesus coming unto him and
saith
behold the lamb of God which taketh away
the sins or the sin of the world. It was
God's
lamb that took away our sin. Y'all put a
one in the chat if you're following so
far. It was God's lamb that took away
our sins. We ought to be thankful for
this because the Bible tells us in
Romans chapter 6
23 that the wages of sin is
death but the gift of God is eternal
life through Jesus Christ our Lord. And
so Jesus came into this
world. He came into this world as as a
sacrifice. His name was called Jesus. He
is known as the son of David. And again
in Matthew 1:21, we find the Bible
saying the book of the generations of
Jesus Christ, the son of
David, the son of
Abraham. Why is Jesus
called the son of
David? That's what we want to find out
today.
How does his birth lead to the taking
away of our
sins which we
earned? Because the wages of sin is
death. To understand this, to understand
why Jesus is called the son of David and
how this term son of David encapsulates
so much in the plan of salvation, we
need to go back to David's
story. And that's what we're going to
do. Because beloved, no one knows more
about the forgiveness of sins than
David, who wrote these very words in
Psalm 51, beginning with verse one. He
said, "Have mercy upon me, oh
God, according to thy loving kindness,
according unto the multitude of thy
tender mercies. Blot out my
transgressions.
Wash me thoroughly from mine iniquity,
and cleanse me from my sin. For I
acknowledge my transgression, and my sin
is ever before
me. Against thee, thee only have I
sinned, and done this evil in thy
sight, that thou mightest be justified
when thou speakest, and be clear when
thou judgest. Behold, I was shapen in
iniquity. In sin did my mother conceive
me. Behold, thou desireest truth in the
inward
parts, and in the hidden part, thou
shalt make me to know wisdom. Purge me
with hissup, and I shall be clean. Wash
me, and I shall be whiter than snow. No
one knows more about forgiveness, the
forgiveness of
God, the mercy of God, than does David.
And you might ask, why? How? How do you
why do you say this about David? And the
answer is found in the book of 2 Samuel
chap 11. Please note it with me. 2
Samuel
11 beginning with verse 1. 2 Samuel chap
11. The Bible says, "And it came to pass
after the year was expired at the time
when kings go forth to
battle that David sent Joab and his
servants with him and all
Israel. And they destroyed the children
of Ammon and besieged Rabba." But David
carried still at Jerusalem.
And it came to pass in the evening tide
that David arose from off his bed and
walked upon the roof of the king's
house. And from the roof he saw a woman
washing herself. And the woman was very
beautiful to look upon. And David sent
and inquired after the woman. And one
said, "Is this is this not
Basheba, the daughter of Iliam, the wife
of Uriah the Hitittite?" And David sent
messengers and took her, and she came in
unto him, and he lay with her, for she
was purified from her uncleanness, and
she returned unto her house. And the
woman conceived and sent and told David,
and said, I am with child. You
understand the dilemma of this
story?
David has just committed the act of
adultery.
He has gotten Bashibba pregnant and now
he is in a
dilemma. What is he going to
do? The Bible tells us that that uh
Basheba was the wife of a man named
Uriah. Note with me verse
6. 2 Samuel 11:6. And David sent to
Joab, saying,
"Send, send me Uriah the Hitittite." And
Joab sent Uriah to David. And when Uriah
was come unto him, David demanded of him
how Joab did, and how the people did,
and how the war prospered. And David
said to Uriah, "Go down to thy house,
and wash thy feet." And Uriah departed
out of the king's house. And there
followed him a mess of meat from the
king. Notice
this. But Uriah slept at the door of the
king's house with all the servants of
his lord, and went not down to his
house. And when they had told David,
saying, Uriah went not down to his
house, David said unto Uriah, Camest
thou not from thy journey? Why then did
thou not go down unto thine house? Verse
11. And Uriah said unto
David, "The ark and Israel and Judah
abide in tents, and my lord Joab and thy
servants of the of thy of my lord are
encamped in the open fields. Shall I
then go into my house to eat and to
drink and to lie with my wife? As thou
livest and as thy soul liveth, I will
not do this thing." Now, let's break
this down for a moment. Let's let's
understand what's going on here.
Uriah is a faithful soldier for
David. He is so
faithful that when David calls him back,
you understand, to set Uriah up, to try
to get Uriah to go and lay with his wife
so that Uriah will ultimately believe
that the pregnancy is his child. Uriah
says, "David, listen. I am so loyal to
you
that it would be
sin for me to go and lay with my wife
while there is a battle going on on your
behalf. Now, I want y'all to think that
through for a
moment. Here David
is
betraying one of his
own that is so faithful to
him that is such a right hand man to
him that he
refuses to even go lay with his
wife while his brethren are on the
battlefield fighting on behalf of
David. Now watch this going back to the
screen. Verse 12. And David said to
Uriah, "Tarry here today also tomorrow.
I will let you depart." And so Uriah
abode in Jerusalem that day and
tomorrow. And when David had called him,
he did eat and drink before him, and
made him drunk. And at evening, he went
out to lie on his bed with the servants
of his lord, but went not down to his
house.
Uriah even in his drunken state was
like,
"Nah, my loyalties are with
David." And so what happens? The Bible
says in verse 14, "And it came to pass
in the morning that David wrote a letter
to Joab and sent it by the hand of
Uriah. And he wrote in the letter
saying, "Set Uriah in the forefront of
the hottest battle and retire from him
that he may be smitten and
die."
Wow. Just
wow. Now, hold on a
moment because I want to pull a a a
lesson from this. And in order to pull
that lesson, you're going to need to see
something.
Because the name Uriah, let's go to the
screen. The name
Uriah, as you can see here from the
Strong's concordance, literally means
flame of
Jah. Flame of Jah. Beloved, when you
think about the day of Pentecost when
fire fell down upon the disciples, I
want you to understand that that was the
flame of Jah. So, let's break that down
for a moment. And if you if y'all are
already a step ahead of me, I need you
to hit that subscribe button or that
share button or that like button because
y'all about to get something very
powerful. You see, beloved, the Holy
Spirit is to us like that right-hand man
that will do anything for us to
succeed. Flame of God.
But I want you to understand, beloved,
that when David does wrong, when David
does wrong, every time he thinks of
Uriah, it's like this burning conviction
in his
heart, this burning conviction in his
mind. The spirit of God, the flame of
God will not leave him
alone. Are y'all catching this? The
flame of God will not leave him alone.
But what is David now trying to do? He's
trying to get rid of the flame of
God. He's trying to quiet his
conscience. He's trying to remove that
conviction. He's trying to kill the
flame of jaw. How many of
us in our pursuit of
sin, in our pursuit of the things that
are designed to separate us from
God, how many of us so often try to
quiet the flame of
jaw? How many of us do exactly what the
text says in the book of Ephesians
chapter 4 and verse 30?
grieve not the Holy Spirit of
God, whereby you are sealed unto the day
of
redemption. How many of us don't realize
that the spirit of God has been sent to
us to fight for us, to protect us? The
spirit of God says, "I'm not leaving
you. I will do nothing to leave you. No,
I will sleep outside of your door at
night. I will listen. I while you are in
battle, while you are in conflict, while
you are fighting for your soul, the
flame of
jaw, the flame of jaw says, "I will not
leave you nor forsake you." And the only
way, beloved, we can get rid of the
flame of jaw is to silence
him. Are y'all with me so far? The only
way we can get rid of the flame of jaw
is to shut him out. Is to try to
distance ourselves and in essence kill
the voice of the spirit to our minds.
And how many of us have been guilty of
doing this very same
thing? David and trying to cover up his
sin.
David in trying to hide his sin gets rid
of the
convicting presence of the flame of
Jah. And you know
what? David lives life covered
up. Perhaps for the next several days,
we're not told, but the next several
days, the next several weeks, the next
several months, David is living as
though nothing has
happened. Everything is good. In fact,
in verse
27, after the news hits uh uh um Basheba
that his her husband is dead, the Bible
says, "And when the morning was passed,
David sent and fetched her to his house,
and she became his wife and bare him a
son. But the thing that David had done
displeased the Lord." Please understand,
beloved, that God is always watching.
God always
sees. And even though David had rejected
the spirit of
ja, God does not give up on David.
Somebody needs to say amen. God did not
give up on David. He sent the prophet
Nathan to him.
Understand that the prophet the prophets
represent the spirit of prophecy which
is the Holy
Spirit. And so even though God David had
rejected the spirit of God in one form,
the spirit of God fighting for
David comes at him again. How many of
you praise God that God doesn't leave
you alone? How many of you praise God
that he doesn't just forsake you, that
he continues to fight for you and he
never gives up on
us? So the prophet Nathan comes to David
and we see in 2 Samuel chapter 12, here
is how the approach happens. Here is how
the confrontation happens. The Bible
says, "And the Lord sent Nathan unto
David and he came unto him and said unto
him, there were two men in one city, the
one rich and the other poor. The rich
man had exceeding many flocks and herds,
but the poor man had nothing, saving one
little u lamb, which he brought and
nourished up. And it grew up together
with him, and with his children, and it
did eat his own meat, and drank of his
own cup, and lay in his bosom, and was
as unto him a daughter.
And there came a traveler unto the rich
man, and he spared to take of his own
flock, of his own herd, to dress for the
wayfairing man that was come unto him,
but took the poor man's lamb, and
dressed it for the man that was come to
him. And David's anger was greatly
kindled against the man, and he said to
Nathan, "As the Lord liveth, the man
that has done this thing shall surely
die." Y'all get what's going on
here? Nathan lays out this parable. He
says there was one man that had
everything and another man that had
nothing. All he had was this one little
lamb and the lamb was to him as his own
blood. And so a wayfairing man comes
along and the rich man instead of
sacrificing one of his own lambs takes
this poor man's lamb and sacrifices
him. Obviously Nathan is relaying
exactly what David the king of Israel
had done to Uriah.
David had everything at his fingertips.
But what does he do? He takes Uriah's
wife. And David's response is, "The man
who did this thing, the man who who who
in this account you're telling me,
Nathan, has taken somebody else's
belonging, that man should David
pronounces judgment upon himself without
knowing it."
Might I add a lesson
here? Might I add something much
deeper? Because you see, beloved, it is
because of our
sin that God had to give up his
lamb, his beloved
son. Note the text again. John 1:29.
Behold the
lamb. Not
of
Tina, not of
Gabriel, not of
Harry. The lamb of
God, God's
lamb. Behold the lamb of
God that takes away the sin of the
world.
In this parable, this lamb was used to
feed the wayfairing
man. I want you to understand in this
very same sense, the Bible says in John
6:53, Jesus said unto them, "Verily,
verily, I say unto you, except you eat
the flesh of the son of man and drink
his blood, you have no life in you."
What I want you to understand, beloved,
is that this this story of of of of
of David is going to give us incredible
insight as to what Jesus himself did on
our behalf. Watch, watch, follow along.
Remember, David has just said, "The man
who does this should die." David
confesses it with his own mouth.
I think back to Proverbs where where
where the son of God is described as
being brought up with the father as
being uh uh from his youth almost as if
the description of this lamb who was
brought up. The only thing he had was
Islam is in
fact a
powerful
parallel to to the lamb of
God who had to be given up on account of
our
sin. And so and so remember remember
what happens.
David's anger was greatly kindled verse
5 against the man and said to Nathan,
"As the Lord liveth, the man that has
done this thing shall surely die, and he
shall restore the lamb four-fold because
he did this thing and because he had no
pity." And Nathan said to David, "Thou
art the
man, thus say the Lord God of Israel, I
anointed thee king over Israel, and I
delivered thee out of the hand of Saul."
You know, he goes on to say, he goes on
to just rebuke David. And then I want
you to check this out because in verse
13, after the rebuke, David says unto
Nathan, I have sinned against the Lord.
Let's pause for a second. Let's just
come back to the screen. David says to
Nathan, he acknowledges his sin. He
says, I have sinned against the
Lord. Beloved, that is something so
crucial.
We ought to acknowledge our sin when we
sin against the Lord. And I want you to
note the very next verse. Nathan said
unto David, "The Lord has put away thy
sin. Thou shalt not die." Y'all go
ahead and put a one in the
chat. Put a one in the chat. If you are
thankful for the mercy of God, put a one
in the chat. If you are thankful for the
mercy of God, I'm going to ask my my
tech team if they could refresh my uh
reream link because it is it's now
paused. I know that everybody is still
on and watching, but I I just cannot see
it. So, team, if you could refresh that
um uh the reream link for me, that would
be
great. The Lord
forgives David.
The prophet
says, "The Lord has put away thy sin.
Thou shalt not die." But here's what I
need you to understand, beloved, that
all sin comes at a cost. All sin comes
at a cost. Put hit subscribe if you're
following what I'm saying. Hit the share
button if you're understanding the
gravity of what you're hearing and what
you are about to hear. Because I want
you to note with me that David is
forgiven. David is forgiven. The Bible
says, the Bible says, uh, in
fact, the very next verse, and and I,
wow, I cannot believe I don't even have
this in my
slide, but verse 14, if someone can put
that in the in the chat for me, that
would be excellent. Verse
14, the Bible says that though David was
forgiven, watch this, the child that
Basheba was pregnant with was would
die. The child would die. Watch this
now. David gets to live, but the
child
dies. Come on, y'all. Come on, watch
this. Isaiah 53:3 and 4. The Bible says
of Jesus, "He is despised and rejected
of men, a man of sorrows and acquainted
with our grief, and we hid as it were
our faces from him. He was despised and
we esteemed him not. Surely he has borne
our griefs and carried our sorrows. Yet
we did esteem him stricken, smitten of
God, and afflicted." Listen to me.
Listen to
me.
David. David.
lives but the child
dies. I need you to understand the
significance because the child died on
the seventh day. He would have been
named on the eighth day had he lived
that long. But he died on the seventh
day after his birth. Meaning he never
got a name. So all we know about this
child is that the child was a male
child and this male
child would then be known as the son of
David. The son of
David. This son of David was brought
into the
world on
account of somebody else's sin.
And though he was innocent and had done
no
wrong, he
dies in the
place of the innocent. In the place of
the
guilty. The innocent dies in the place
of the guilty. And now I need you to
understand something called
justification by
faith. Because this is what the story of
the son of David teaches us.
The lamb of God was brought into this
world on
account of our sins. And though he was
innocent, the son of David died that we
might
live. This is what is called
justification by faith. Jesus died to
justify us. You all put a share. Hit
that share button if you understand the
point. Don't say amen, hit share. Hit
share. Don't say amen. Hit
like. Help others to
understand how unfair it
is that we get to
live while the son of God died in our
place that we might
live. But beloved, that is the mercy of
God. That is the mercy of God. And so
here is the story of the son of David.
But the son of David's story does not
end there. You may have even heard me
share this before, but listen to me. The
son of David's story does not end there.
Let's go back to the screen. Let's go
back to the screen. He was wounded for
our transgressions. He was bruised for
our iniquities. The chastisement of our
peace was upon him. And with his
stripes, we are healed. All we like
sheep have gone astray and have turned
to his own way. And the Lord laid on him
the iniquity of us all. He took that
iniquity. Now watch this.
So the son of David dies but that is not
the end of the son of David because the
Bible says in 2 Samuel verse 12 24 after
this death David comforted Basheba his
wife and went in unto her and lay with
her and she bare a son and he called his
name
Solomon and the Lord loved him and he
sent by the hand of Nathan the prophet
and called his name Jedodiah because of
the
Lord. So the son of David does not end
with the son of David because the son of
David analogy continues on now in the
form of
Solomon. The name Jedodiah literally
means the loved of God. The loved of
God. which is so interesting because in
Matthew 3:16-1 17 the Bible says and
when Jesus was baptized he went up
straightway out of the water and lo the
heavens were open unto him and he saw
the spirit of God descending like a dove
and lighting upon him and lo a voice
from heaven saying this is my beloved
son in whom I am well
pleased you see beloved not only was the
first son of David a type of Jesus's uh
uh uh coming into this world on account
of our sin and dying that we might be
saved. But then the next son of David,
Solomon, continues the
type. You say, "How pastor, please note,
please note verse 12. First Kings
2:12, then sat Solomon upon the throne
of David his father, and his kingdom was
established greatly." Are y'all catching
this? Are y'all catching
this? When does Jesus sit on the throne
of his
father? It is when he ascends to heaven.
So watch this then. Under the first son
of David, you have here the type of
Jesus being brought into the world on
account of somebody else's sin and died
even though he was innocent. died on
behalf of the guilty that the guilty
might live. That is the first son of
David. The story then picks up with the
second son of David,
Solomon, who ascends to the throne of
his
father. Do y'all catch this? In these
two sons of David, you have one picture
of the son of
David who came into this world on
account of somebody else's sin, died in
our place that we might might live and
then ascend to his father's
throne. H watch this. It doesn't stop
there. It doesn't stop there. What does
he do once he's on the throne? Notice
with me first Kings chapter 3 2 and 4
2-4. So the Bible says only the people
sacrificed in high places because there
was no house built in unto the name of
the Lord until those days. And Solomon
loved the Lord walking in the statutes
of David his father. Only he sacrificed
and burnt in high places. And the king
went to Gibian to sacrifice there. For
that there for that was the great high
place. A thousand burnt offerings did
Solomon offer upon a ram. In Gibian, the
Lord I'm
sorry, we're gonna just skip that verse
I just read. We're gonna focus on this
verse. In Gibian, the Lord appeared unto
Solomon in the dream by night and said
as this is this is afterward. Okay? So,
so let's just go back and I want I don't
want to lose you here. So Solomon
ascends to his father's throne and the
correct verse we should have just read
is right
here. As he's about to take rule, the
Bible says verse five, in Gibian, the
Lord appeared to Solomon in dream by a
night. In a dream by night. And God
said, "Ask what I shall give thee." And
Solomon said, "Thou hast showed unto thy
servant David, my father great mercy,
according as he walked before thee in
truth and in righteousness, and an
uprightness of heart with thee. And thou
has kept for him this great kindness,
that thou has given him a son to sit on
his throne, as it is this day." Okay,
watch
this. Give therefore thy servant an
understanding heart to judge thy people,
that I may
discern that I may
discern
between good and bad. For who is able to
judge this thy so great a people?
Hm. What is Jesus rece what is Solomon
I'm sorry. What is Solomon
receiving as
he
enters as he sits upon his father's
throne. Judgment's going to be given
unto
him. Judgment's going to be given unto
him.
Not only will this be part of his work,
but but let's notice First Kings chapter
5:1. First Kings chapter 5:1. And Hyram,
king of Ty, sent his servants unto
Solomon, for he had heard that they had
anointed him king in the room of his
father. For Hyram was ever a lover of
David. And Solomon sent to Hyram,
saying, Thou knowest how that David my
father could not build a house unto the
name of the Lord his God, for the wars
which were about him on every side,
until the Lord put them under the souls
of his feet. Watch this. But now the
Lord my God has given me rest on every
side, so that there is neither adversary
nor evil occurren. And behold, I
purposed to build and a house unto the
name of the Lord my God. As the Lord
spake unto David my father, saying, "Thy
son, whom I will set upon thy throne in
thy room, he shall build an house unto
my name." So, I want you to check this
out,
y'all. Solomon, the first son of David,
was brought into the world on account of
someone else's sin. died that the guilty
might live even though he was innocent.
The second son of
David, ascends to the throne of his
father and is commissioned to prepare a
place. Y'all go ahead and put a
share. Hit that share button if you
understand what I just said.
Hit that like button if you're like,
"Oh, wait a minute. What just
happened?" Solomon is commissioned to
prepare a
place. Yes. If you're thinking, beloved,
with me, John 14 verse 1-3, which reads,
"Let not your heart be troubled. You
believe in God, believe also in me. In
my father's house are many mansions. If
it were not so, I would have told you. I
go to prepare a place for you. And if I
go and prepare a place for you, I will
come again and receive you unto myself,
that where I am, there you may be. Also,
I need you to understand that when you
put the stories of the two sons of David
together, you're actually seeing a
picture of the one son of
David. You're actually seeing a picture
of Jesus who ascended to the throne of
his father to build a place to build a
place for us to build a house on behalf
of his father. And this is why the
beloved, the Bible says in Zechariah
chapter 6:12, "Behold the man whose name
is the branch. He shall build the temple
of the Lord, even he shall build the
temple of the Lord, and he shall bear
the glory and shall sit and rule upon
his throne." Or there is Ephesians
chapter 2 19 which says now therefore
you are of the household of God and are
built upon the foundation of the
apostles and prophets Jesus Christ
himself being the chief cornerstone in
whom all the building fitly framed
together groweth unto a holy temple in
the Lord. So here's what I need you to
understand. Not only has Jesus gone to
build a place for us in heaven, but he's
also building a house for God on
earth. What do you mean building a
house for God on earth? Well, let me
show you. 1 Corinthians 3:16 tells it
plainly, "Know you not that you are the
temple of God, and that the spirit of
God dwelleth in you? If any man defile
the temple, him shall God destroy. For
the temple of God is holy, which temple
you are. Beloved, watch this. Jesus is
building a house in heaven for us, and
he's building a house on earth for
God. That's what the son of David is
doing.
This is why the Bible says in 1 Peter
chapter 2:4 and 5, to whom coming as
unto a living stone, ye also as lively
stones are built up a spiritual house, a
holy priesthood. And Colossians 2:6
says, "As you therefore have received
Christ Jesus the Lord, so walk ye in
him, rooted and built up in him, and
established in the faith, as you have
been taught, abounding therein with
thanksgiving." So beloved, this building
of the temple is what we would now call
sanctification. So watch
this. In the first son of David, you
have the picture of
justification. Jesus dying on our
behalf. Even though we were guilty, he
dies in our place that we may live. the
first son of David, the one that has no
name, the one that died on the seventh
day and therefore was not aimed named on
the eighth day. So all we know of him is
that he's the son of David. That first
son signifies justification by faith.
Whereas the second son of David,
Solomon, is now building. He's doing a
work that is progressive, that is going
on and on and on, which signifies the
the the the the walk of sanctification
or the work of sanctification in the
Christian life. If you're with me so
far, if you
appreciate what you have heard, what you
are hearing, what are you supposed to
do? You're supposed to hit that share
button. You're supposed to hit that like
button. You're supposed to say, "How can
we get others to hear what we are
hearing right now?" Beloved, listen to
me. In the two sons of David, you have
not only a picture of Jesus in his
birth, life, death, burial, but you also
have a picture of Jesus in his
resurrection, ascension to heaven,
sitting on the throne of his father and
and and and and preparing a place not
only for for uh for us in heaven, but
for his father on earth. Are y'all with
me so far? That work signifies
sanctification. Whereas the work of the
first son of David signifies
justification. Now, now I want you to
note this because there is something
that happens. D the son of David uh gets
to the place where he's about to do the
finishing touches on the work of the
sanctuary. And what does the Bible tell
us about this last work? Please note
with me First Kings chapter 8. The Bible
says in verse one, "Then Solomon
assembled the elders of Israel and all
the heads of the tribes, the chief of
the fathers of the children of Israel
unto the king unto King Solomon in
Jerusalem, that they might bring up the
ark of the covenant of the Lord out of
the city of David, which is in Zion. And
all the men of Israel assembled
themselves unto the King Solomon at the
feast in the month Enom, which is in the
seventh month.
Uh, and the elders of Israel came, and
the priests took up the ark, and they
brought up the ark of the of the Lord,
and the tabernacle of the congregation,
and all the holy vessels that were in
the tabernacle. Even these did the
priests and the Levites bring up. And
King Solomon, and all the congregation
of Israel that were assembled unto him
were with him before the ark,
sacrificing sheep and oxen that could
not be told for number. I need y'all to
understand. I need y'all to understand
what's going on here. Let's keep
reading. And the priest brought the ark
of the covenant of the Lord unto his
place, into the oracle of the house, to
the most holy place, even under the
wings of the cherubams. For the cherubam
spread forth their two wings over the
place of the ark, and the cherubams
covered the ark, and the stabs thereof
above. Keep reading. Oh, no, no, no.
Let's not keep reading. Let's pause for
a second. Y'all come back. Y'all come
back. How y'all
doing? How are y'all
doing? The final work of
Solomon in structuring the temple was
bringing the
ark into the
temple. Is that not the closing work of
the gospel? I saw another angel flying
in the midst of heaven having the
everlasting gospel to preach unto every
nation kindred and tongue with a loud
voice saying fear God and give glory to
him for the hour of his judgment is come
and worship him that made heaven the
earth the sea and the fountains of
waters isn't the work of God isn't the
work of Jesus to write the law in the
hark in the hark that is not my Jamaican
accent of saying ark it is a word I'm
making up to to combine the word heart
with ark in the ark. Is not the work of
Jesus to put the law of God in the ark?
Is not that the new
covenant? Is the seal of God not to seal
the law among his disciples?
It is such a powerful thought that in
this story of the son of David, which is
actually broken up into two sons of
David, we have the story of Jesus's
birth, life, death, burial, resurrection
on our behalf, his ascension into heaven
into his onto his father's throne. his
his work of building a temple in heaven
for us while building a house for God on
this earth in our hearts that when he
closes the work the final work will be
the ark that is brought into will be the
law of God that has been brought into
the
heart Revelation 11:18 the Bible says
and the nations were angry and thy wrath
has come in the time of the dead that
they should be judged that thou should
give reward unto thy servants of
prophets and to the saints and them that
fear thy name small and great which
should destroy the them which destroy
the earth and wow I really don't have
verse 19 in here but let me tell it to
you anyway the Bible says the temple of
God was open in heaven and there was
seen the
ark the ark of his
testament beloved could it be that what
we're reading in sec in in in in in the
story of the son of David is that the
final work of the final work of the son
of David has to do with the
ark has to do with the law of God being
placed being brought the the
simultaneously while he's completing the
temple in heaven there is seen in heaven
the ark of his testament and while he's
completing the temples on earth he is
bringing to the minds of the people and
to the hearts of the people. The law of
God, thy will be done on earth as it is
in
heaven. And now watch
this. After the ark has been placed in
the tabernacle, what happens next? What
happens
next? What happens next?
First Kings chapter 8:10 tells us, "And
it came to pass when the priests were
come out of the holy place that the
cloud filled the house of the Lord. So
that the priests could not stand to
minister because of the cloud. For the
glory of the Lord had filled the house
of the Lord. The glory of God was so
powerful." Come on
y'all. Come on y'all.
When the work was
finished, the spirit of God fills the
temple. Later, somebody the spirit of
God fills the temple. Beloved, we can
understand the significance of this
because in Revelation 15:8, the Bible
says, "And the temple was filled with
the smoke from the glory of God and from
his power." Notice it on the screen. And
no man was able to enter into the temple
till the seven plagues of the seven
angels were fulfilled. So I need y'all
to understand
this in a spiritual sense. When the
spirit of God fills the temple on
earth, no it's sealed. Nobody can enter
into
it. When the spirit of God, when the
glory of God fills the temple in heaven,
it's time for the plagues to
fall. What a powerful parallel, y'all.
What a powerful parallel. And and here's
what's so powerful about
it. Watch this. Let's go back to the
screen. First Kings chapter 9 vers 1 and
2. And it came to pass when Solomon had
finished building the house of the Lord
and the king's house and all Solomon's
desires which he had pleased to do that
the Lord appeared to Solomon the second
time. So this is the second appearing of
the
Lord. This is the second appearing of
the Lord. So Christ was offered to bear
the sins of many like the first son of
David. and unto them that look to him
that shall he appear the second time
without sin unto
salvation. It is when Solomon finishes
the work that a Lord that the Lord
appears to him the second time, the
second appearing of the
Lord. Beloved, we have not believed
cunningly
devised
fables. You can't make this stuff
up. The beauty of God is all through the
scriptures, you
guys. It it it's a sad thing to me when
people say, "Yeah, I don't see that. You
know, we got it
wrong." We're not following the
Bible. Is this really the truth? Is it
really? It's a sad
thing because how can this storyline be
in thousands of places in the
scripture right there before our eyes?
The problem is many of us are not
looking. We're not feeding off of living
mana. Now, beloved, believe it or not.
Believe it or
not, the sermon is about to
begin. I'm not going to keep you much
longer, but I'm just saying all of that
was to build up to
this. So, everything you've heard before
was really just to get to this point
that you're about to hear
now. I just had to lay out to you so
that you could see. Yeah, true, true,
true, true,
true. So that when I share with you this
part, hopefully it'll
offer a piece to you that passes
understanding. So here's the
part. Here's the
part. So let's go to First Kings chapter
10. So this is this is all chronological
order, right? This is all chronological
order. But here's what happened in First
Kings chapter 10. And when the Queen of
Sheba heard of the fame of Solomon
concerning the name of the
Lord, she came to prove him with hard
questions. So remember now this is first
kings chapter 10. So let's go back.
First Kings chapter 9, Solomon finishes
the temple. You see that, right? So I'm
not making up. First Kings chapter 9 is
where Solomon finishes the temple is
where the Lord appears again the second
time. And then first Kings chapter 10,
the Queen of
Sheba, when she had heard of the fame
concerning the name of the Lord, she
came to prove him that is Solomon, the
son of David, with hard questions. And
she came to Jerusalem with a very great
train with camels that bear spices and
very much gold and precious
stones. If we're following the pattern,
if we're following the
pattern, we see the pattern in
Revelation 21:4, verse 24. and the
nations of them which are saved shall
walk in the light of it. And the kings
of the earth do bring their glory and
honor to it. So remember, Sheba, the
queen of Sheba, is now coming because
she's heard of the fame of Solomon and
she's got a lot of questions for
Solomon. She
does. When she came when she was come to
Solomon, she communed with him of all
that was in her heart. And Solomon told
told her all her questions, there was
not anything hid from the king which he
told her not. And when the Queen of
Sheba had seen all Solomon's wisdom, and
the house that he had built, and the
meat of his table, and the sitting of
his servants, are
y'all who are y'all following this,
y'all? when she saw the glory of his
kingdom with her own eyes and the
attendance of his ministers and their
apparel and his cupbearers and his
ascent by which he went up to the house
of the Lord. There was no more spirit in
her. And she said to the king, "It was a
true report that I heard in my own land
of thy acts and of thy wisdom. How be it
I believe not the words until I came and
mine eyes had seen it. And behold, the
half was not told me. Thy wisdom and thy
prosperity exceeded the thing which I
heard, eye has not seen, nor has ear
heard, nor has entered into the hearts
of men the things which God has prepared
for them that love him. And listen to
me, y'all. Listen to
me. When we go to see
Jesus, we're going to commune with him.
all the things of our
hearts, all the
questions, the hard questions. Lord, why
did this have to happen this
way? Lord, why did
I why did I have to
lose my
brother at such a young
age? Lord, he's
51. He followed the health
message. Lord, help me to understand.
I know the
promises. I know it,
Lord. But help me to understand because
it doesn't make sense to
me. When you have those hard
questions, when you have those hard
questions, Lord, why did I lose my son?
Why did I lose my daughter? Why did this
happen the way that it
happened? There's coming that time where
we get to ask the son of
David and he will tell us and our minds
will be
blown. We will we will truly
see that eye has not seen nor has
entered into the hearts of men the
things that God has prepared for them.
Yes, Robert, better is one
day with the Lord in your courts than
thousands elsewhere.
You can rest
assured that those who who accepted the
work of the son of
David, those who accepted the work of
the son of David in justification and
those who accept the work of the son of
David in in in in
sanctification will go on to be able to
ask the son of David all their hard
questions.
What a what an assuring
promise that is going to be. That
is. So when I was little, when I was
little, five years
old, my father and mother left me and my
brother in
Jamaica. And I want you to note how I
said that. Okay.
Um they left us in Jamaica. We were left
there for about six
months. And during that time I I was too
I didn't
understand I didn't understand that they
were coming to America
to make a better place to bring us to
have to have a better life. I didn't
understand that that they were making
sacrifices for me. I just thought that
they left us.
So, five months later when we are
arriving in America for the first time
and my little brother Shawn, we see our
parents in the airport. My little
brother Shawn runs to my mom and I run
to my dad and I'm running to my dad and
there's one thing on my
mind and I guess I was stewing about
this the whole plane ride
there. When I when I saw my dad, I ran
to him. He's smiling. He's just like so
excited to see me. And he scoops me up
in his arm. I jump and he catches and
scoops me up in his arm. And I take my
fist and I punch my dad right in the
chest. And my first words to him were,
"Why did you leave
me?" I may as well have said, "Why had
you Why did you forsake me?
And my father just held
me. He wasn't mad at the punch. But he
knew something. He knew that I was too
little. Listen to me what I'm saying,
you guys. He knew that I was too little
to
understand. He knew that I was too
little to
understand why we had to leave. He knew
that I was too little to understand all
the all the intricacies. My mind could
not fathom. All I thought was he forsook
me. My parents forsook
me. Nothing could have been further from
the
truth. There are many of us walking
around today
thinking, "God, why did you forsake
me? Why did you leave me? We're mad.
were
angry. Lord, why did you leave me? Why?
Why was I allowed to suffer the things
that I
suffered? And I want you to understand
something. We are too young to
understand. Did you all hear what I
said? We are too young to You're like,
"But pastor, I'm I'm 75." Yeah, that's
nothing compared to eternity. We are too
young to
understand. But the time is coming when
we will
understand. Where we will get to see the
son of David face to face and ask him
all of our hard
questions. All of our hard
questions. And when we see the king in
his
glory, when we see with our own eyes,
let me finish reading first kings
chapter chapter 10 verse 8 and n. Happy
are thy men. Happy are thy are these thy
servants which stand continually before
thee and hear thy wisdom. Blessed be the
Lord thy God which delightth in thee to
set thee on the throne of Israel.
Because the Lord loved Israel forever.
Therefore made he king to do justice, to
do judgment and
justice. Listen to me.
The Queen of Sheba's
plea, the Queen of Sheba's
words, her
reaction to seeing the Son of David is a
parallel to the joy we will
experience when we see the Son of David.
When we get all of our hard questions
answered, when we see the king in all
his glory, we will say the half was not
told
us. If it is your desire to see the king
with your own eyes and all his glory in
his
kingdom, now I'm going to ask you to put
that one in the chat as we close out in
prayer. I pray that this message would
have encouraged you today. Not only
encouraged you to go to go deeper into
the word of God. not only encouraged you
to allow the son of David to build this
house for God, not only has it
encouraged you to accept the
justification which he offers us, the
sanctification which he offers
us, but but that it will encourage you
to hold on because all your hard
questions, the ones that we do not have
answers for here on this earth, will be
answered and we will get to
Today that half has not been
told about the glory that awaits us in
that
kingdom. Heavenly
Father, thank you for speaking to us.
Thank you for showing us the beauty of
your word. Thank you for showing us that
the scriptures are truly centered on
Jesus. And above all, Lord, thank you
for letting us
know that we will not have to sit always
with these hard
questions. They will be
answered. Lord, only allow us the
opportunity to enter into your kingdom
to see that glory and to ask those
questions. Thank you, Lord. Thank you
for your amazing grace and your amazing
love toward us. Bless us and draw us as
our prayer in Jesus name. May we not
fight the spirit of jaw, the spirit of
God, but may we embrace it that we may
be saved at last is our prayer in Jesus
name. Amen. And amen. May God bless you.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch. We are not just here
for Sabbath service. We have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health, physical health, weekly prayer
service, financial health, and proving
the existence of God. It is our desire
that our programming will continue to
bless you. Please continue to pray for
us as we fulfill God's mission to go
into all the world with the gospel of
Jesus Christ.
[Music]